<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[falconzy's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://falconzy.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://falconzy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-31T23:42:53+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://falconzy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ian Zhao]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[ian@zhaoyan.me]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OAuth 2.0]]></title>
    <link href="http://falconzy.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/oauth-2-dot-0/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-28T16:16:51+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://falconzy.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/oauth-2-dot-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Summaries on :
OAuth 2.0 – The Good, The Bad &amp; The Ugly
<a href="http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/oauth-2-0-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/">http://net.tutsplus.com/tutorials/oauth-2-0-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/</a></p>

<h2>What is OAuth?</h2>

<p>OAuth is an open standard for authorization. OAuth provides a method for clients to access server resources on behalf of a resource owner (such as a different client or an end-user). It also provides a process for end-users to authorize third-party access to their server resources without sharing their credentials (typically, a username and password pair), using user-agent redirections.</p>

<p>OAuth is a service that is complementary to, and therefore distinct from, OpenID. OAuth is also distinct from OATH, which is a reference architecture for authentication (i.e. not a standard).</p>

<h2>Key Words of OAuth</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>Resource Owner</strong> : An entity capable of granting access to a protected resource. Most of the time, it’s an end-user.</li>
<li><strong>Client</strong> : An application making protected resource requests on behalf of the resource owner and with its authorization. It can be a server-based, mobile (native) or a desktop application.</li>
<li><strong>Resource Server</strong> : The server hosting the protected resources, capable of accepting and responding to protected resource requests.</li>
<li><strong>Authorization Server</strong> : The server issuing access grants/tokens to the client after successfully authenticating the resource owner and obtaining authorization.</li>
<li><strong>Access Token</strong> : Access tokens are credentials presented by the client to the resource server to access protected resources. It’s normally a string consisting of a specific scope, lifetime and other access attributes and it may self contain the authorization information in a verifiable manner.</li>
<li><strong>Refresh Token</strong> : Although not mandated by the spec, access tokens ideally have an expiration time which can last anywhere from a few minutes to several hours. Once an access token is expired, the client can request the authorization server to issue a new access token using the refresh token issued by the authorization server.</li>
</ul>


<h2>OAuth 2.0 in Depth</h2>

<p>Before initiating the protocol, the client must <em>register with the authorization server</em> by providing its client type, its redirection URL (where it wants the authorization server to redirect to after the resource owner grants or rejects the access) and any other information required by the server and in turn, is given a client identifier and client secret (client_secret). This process is known as <strong>Client Registration</strong>.</p>

<h2>The Web Server Flow</h2>

<p>Since this is a redirection-based flow, the client must be able to interact with the resource owner’s user agent (which in most cases is a web browser) and hence is typically suited for a web application. The below diagram is a bird’s eye view of how the end-user (or the resource owner) uses the client application (web-server based application in this case) to authenticate and authorize with the authorization server, in order to access the resources protected by the resource server.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://falconzy.github.io/images/web_server_flow.jpg" width="600" height="450" title="Web Server Flow" ></p>

<h2>Authenticate &amp; Authorize the Client</h2>

<p><a href="https://developers.google.com/oauthplayground/">https://developers.google.com/oauthplayground/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setup a Octopress Blog With Github]]></title>
    <link href="http://falconzy.github.io/blog/2013/12/26/hello-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-26T20:42:38+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://falconzy.github.io/blog/2013/12/26/hello-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Follow the Gudie: </h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/setup/">Octopress Setup</a></li>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/configuring/">Configuration</a></li>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/">Blog Posts</a></li>
<li><a href="http://octopress.org/docs/deploying/github/">Deploying to Github Pages</a></li>
<li><a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/basics">Markdown: Basics</a></li>
</ul>


<h2>Troubleshooting</h2>

<hr />

<p>Here are some problem i face during the <em>installation and setup</em> process,hope it helps you:</br></p>

<h2>Error 1</h2>

<blockquote><p>You have already activated rake 10.1.1, but your Gemfile requires rake 0.9.2.2. Using bundle exec may solve this.</p>

<h2>solution :</h2>

<p>modify the &ldquo;Gemfile&rdquo;, changed to
<code>gem &lsquo;rake&rsquo;, &lsquo;~> 10.1.1&rsquo;</code></p></blockquote>

<h2>Error 2</h2>

<blockquote><p>Fail to deply when run &ldquo;rake deploy&rdquo;</p>

<h2>solution :</h2>

<p><code>
when Octopress runs commond rake depoly, it will push two brance to Github, one call &ldquo;source&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s all your octopress code, another call &ldquo;master&rdquo;, it&rsquo;s the gernerated html file to display your website. need to make sure all your brance up to date before you run &ldquo;rake deploy&rdquo;.
</code></p></blockquote>

<h2>Extra Reading</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://webdesign.tutsplus.com/tutorials/applications/getting-started-with-octopress/">Getting Started with Octopress</a></li>
<li><a href="https://help.github.com/articles/github-flavored-markdown">GitHub Flavored Markdown</a></li>
<li><a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax">MarkDown Syntax</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.moncefbelyamani.com/how-to-install-and-configure-octopress-on-a-mac/">How to Install &amp; Configure Octopress on a Mac, and Host Your Static Website on Amazon S3</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.darkcoding.net/software/markdown-quick-reference/">Markdown quick reference</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
